Guide to the May McEwen Kaiser Company Records, 1913-1948 RL.11111
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
May McEwen Kaiser Company records
1913-1948
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11111
10 Linear Feet 80 volumes
Collection comprises 80 volumes, including account books, balance sheets, trial balances, ledgers, journals, cashbooks, voucher registers, operating ledgers, cost ledgers, sales journals, sales summaries, incomplete stock books, and other records of a Burlington, N.C., manufacturer of rayon, cotton, nylon, and silk hosiery. There are records of the Daisy Hosiery Mills and the May Hosiery Mills, which consolidated under the name May McEwen Kaiser, as well as a chart of accounts that was prepared in 1948.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The May McEwen Kaiser Company Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1966.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises 80 volumes, including account books, balance sheets, trial balances, ledgers, journals, cashbooks, voucher registers, operating ledgers, cost ledgers, sales journals, sales summaries, incomplete stock books, and other records of a Burlington, N.C., manufacturer of rayon, cotton, nylon, and silk hosiery.There are records of the Daisy Hosiery Mills and the May Hosiery Mills, which consolidated under the name May McEwen Kaiser, as well as a chart of accounts that was prepared in 1948.
Biographical / Historical
May McEwen Kaiser Co., Inc., a manufacturer of full-fashioned and seamless rayon, cotton, nylon, and silk hosiery, began in 1913 as the May Hosiery Mills, a co-partnership of William Henry May and his brother, Benjamin Victor May. The early business produced ladies', mens' and children's seamless hosiery. The opening entries of the Journal, 1922-1927, include an explanation of the organization of the May Hosiery Mills, Inc., in 1922 as a consolidation of Daisy Hosiery Mills of Burlington and May Hosiery Mills.
In 1927 the corporation absorbed the National Dye Works of Burlington, another enterprize with which W.H. May was involved.
In December, 1934, May Hosiery acquired two additional manufacturers in Burlington--Mohawk Hosiery Mills and Whitehead Hosiery Mills.
On September 1, 1940, the corporation consolidated with McEwen Knitting Company of Burlington and in December amended its new charter by the adoption of the name of May McEwen Kaiser Company, Inc. Burlington Industries absorbed the company in July, 1948.
The wholly owned subsidiaries of May McEwen Kaiser included the Dothan Silk Hosiery Co. of Dothan, Alabama, and the Grabur Silk Mills, Inc., of Burlington.
In 1945 May McEwen Kaiser formed a new wholly-owned subsidiary, Sidney Knitting Mills, Inc., of Burlington, to absorb the Scott Hosiery Mills of Graham, N.C.
The corporation also owned Vance Knitting Co. of Kernersville, N.C. By 1946 the total assets had grown to more than $10,600,000.
- May Hosiery Mills: Accounts Receivable (1917-1921); Trial Balances (1913-1918, 1921-1922); Inventories (1914-1918, 1921-1922); Outstanding Customers' Notes Acceptances (1919-1922)., 1913-1922 (Volume 1)
- Daisy Hosiery Mills: Accounts Receivable (1917-1922); Trial Balances (1921-1922); Inventories (1921-1922); Outstanding Customers' Notes Acceptances (1919) (Volume 1)
- May Hosiery Mills: Trial Balances (1922-1926); Inventories (1922-1926), 1921-1926 (Volume 2)
- Daisy Hosiery Mills: Trial Balances (1921-1922); Inventories (1921-1922) (Volume 2)
- Sales Journal (May Hosiery Mills), Dec. 1921-May 1928 (Volume 3)
- Sales Journal, Feb. 1920-Dec. 1921 (Volume 4)
- Sales Journal, Feb. 1918-Jan. 1920 (Volume 5)
- Sales Journal (May Hosiery Mills), Nov. 1915-Feb. 1918 (Volume 6)
- Journal (May Hosiery Mills), Mar. 1918-June1922 (Volume 7)
- Journal, July 1922-Aug. 1927 (Volume 8)
- Journal, Sept. 1927-Oct. 1929 (Volume 9)
- Journal (May Hosiery Mills), 1929-1934 (Volume 10)
- Journal (May Hosiery Mills), Nov. 1934-Aug. 1937 (Volume 11)
- Journal Entries (May McEwen Kaiser Division of Burlington Mills Corp.), June 1948-Jan. 1949 (Volume 12)
- Ledger, Dec. 1944-Feb. 1948 (Volume 13)
- Stock Registration, 1929-1942 (Volume 14)
- Balance Sheets, Sept. 1927-Nov. 1946 (Volume 15)
- Stock Registration (May Hosiery Mills), Sept. 1927-May 1929 (Volume 16)
- Ledger (May Hosiery Mills - contains note: "Name changed to May McEwen Kaiser Co. Jan. 1, 1941", Sept. 1940-Nov. 1944 (Volume 17)
- Ledger (May Hosiery Mills), 1918-1922 (Volume 18)
- Ledger, July 1922-Aug. 1927 (Volume 19)
- Journal, Aug. 1937-May 1939 (Volume 20)
- Journal, May 1939-Nov. 1942 (Volume 21)
- Journal, Dec. 1942-Nov. 1946 (Volume 22)
- Journal, Dec. 1946-June 1948 (Volume 23)
- Ledger (May Hosiery Mills), 1913-1915 (Volume 24)
- Ledger (May Hosiery Mills), 1915-1918 (Volume 25)
- Stock Transfer Book (May Hosiery Mills, Inc.), Sept. 1927-Mar. 1935 (Volume 26)
- Stock Transfer Book (May Hosiery Mills, Inc.), Apr. 1935-Jan. 1941 (Volume 27)
- Cashbook, May 1921-June 1922 (Volume 28)
- Cashbook, Oct. 1919-Apr. 1921 (Volume 29)
- Ledger (folders 1-3), Sept. 1927-Aug. 1935 (Volume 30 pt. 1)
- Ledger (folders 4-6), Sept. 1927-Aug. 1935 (Volume 30 pt. 2)
- Ledger, Sept. 1935-Sept. 1940 (Volume 31)
- Cashbook, Oct. 1923-Oct. 1924 (Volume 32)
- Cashbook, Oct. 1924-July 1925 (Volume 33)
- Cashbook, July 1925-June 1926 (Volume 34)
- Cash Book Receipts (May Hosiery Mills), Aug. 1928-Oct. 1929 (Volume 35)
- Cash Book Receipts (May Hosiery Mills), 1929-1930 (Volume 36)
- Cash Book (May Hosiery Mills), 1926-1927 (Volume 37)
- Cash Book (May Hosiery Mills), Apr. 1927-Dec. 1927 (Volume 38)
- Cash Book (May Hosiery Mills), 1922-1923 (Volume 39)
- Cashbook, Dec. 1927-Aug. 1928 (Volume 40)
- Cash Dispursements, Aug. 1928-Oct. 1929 (Volume 41)
- Cash Receipts (folders 1-3), Sept. 1933-Nov. 1947 (Volume 42 pt. 1)
- Cash Receipts (folders 4-6), Sept. 1933-Nov. 1947 (Volume 42 pt.2)
- Cash Receipts (May Hosiery Mills), 1947-1948 (Volume 43)
- Cash Receipts, Oct. 1930-Aug. 1933 (Volume 44 pt. 1)
- Cash Receipts, Oct. 1930-Aug. 1933 (Volume 44 pt. 2)
- Depreciation, Insurance, Payroll Summaries, and Taxes, 1941-1945 (Volume 45)
- Cash Dispursements, 1937-1947 (Volume 46)
- Cash Dispursements (May Hosiery Mills), 1947-1948 (Volume 47)
- Cash Dispursements, Nov. 1929-Aug. 1937 (Volume 48 pt. 1)
- Cash Dispursements (May Hosiery Mills), Nov. 1929-Aug. 1937 (Volume 48 pt. 2)
- Voucher Record (May Hosiery Mills), 1922-1925 (Volume 49)
- Voucher Record (May Hosiery Mills), 1925-1928 (Volume 50)
- Voucher Record (May Hosiery Mills), Apr. 1928-Oct. 1929 (Volume 51)
- Trial Balances (May Hosiery Mills), June 1913-Aug. 1924 (Volume 52)
- Trial Balance Book (May Hosiery Mills), Aug. 1924-Sept. 1927 (Volume 53)
- Trial Balance Book (May Hosiery Mills), Sept. 1929-Aug. 1936 (Volume 54)
- Trial Balance Book (May Hosiery Mills), Sept. 1936-Aug. 1937 (Volume 55)
- Trial Balance Book (May Hosiery Mills), Sept. 1937-Aug. 1940 (Volume 56)
- Trial Balance Book, Sept. 1940-Nov. 1942 (Volume 57)
- Trial Balance Book, Dec. 1942-Nov. 1945 (Volume 58)
- Trial Balance Book, Dec. 1945-June 1948 (Volume 59)
- Voucher Record (May Hosiery Mills), 1918-1919 (Volume 60)
- Voucher Record (May Hosiery Mills), 1920-1922 (Volume 61)
- Trial Balance Book (May Hosiery Mills), Sept. 1927-Aug. 1929 (Volume 62)
- Voucher Register, 1935-1938 (Volume 63)
- Voucher Register, 1929-1935 (Volume 64 pt. 1)
- Voucher Register, 1929-1935 (Volume 64 pt. 2)
- Inventory Book (May Hosiery Mills), Feb. 1926-Aug. 1927 (Volume 65)
- Voucher Register, no dates (Volume 66)
- Voucher Register, 1939-1946 (Volume 67 pt. 1)
- Voucher Register, 1939-1946 (Volume 67 pt. 2)
- Operating Ledger (May Hosiery Mills), 1935-1940 (Volume 68 pt. 1)
- Operating Ledger (May Hosiery Mills), 1935-1940 (Volume 68 pt. 2)
- Operating Ledger, Dec. 1947-Nov. 1948 (Volume 69)
- Cost Ledger, 1935-1945 (Volume 70 pt. 1)
- Cost Ledger, 1935-1945 (Volume 70 pt. 2, 72 pt. 1))
- Operating Ledger, Dec. 1946-Nov. 1947 (Volume 71)
- Operating Ledger, 1940-1944 (Volume 72 pt. 2)
- Operating Ledger, 1940-1944 (Volume 72 pt. 3)
- Depreciation, Insurance, Payroll Summaries, and Taxes, 1935-1941 (Volume 73 pt. 1)
- Payroll Summaries, Depreciation, Insurance, Taxes, Production Record Transfer File, Sept. 1935-Nov. 1941 (Volume 73 pt. 2)
- Operating Ledger, Dec. 1944-Nov. 1946 (Volume 74)
- Payroll Book, Apr. 1943-Dec. 1946 (Volume 75)
- Payroll Book, Jan. 1947-Mar. 1948 (Volume 76)
- Cost Ledger, 1945-1948 (Volume 77)
- May Mills Sales Company of California: Ledger, Trial Balances, Cash Journal, 1939-1941 (Volume 78)
- Sales Summaries, 1945-1948 (Volume 79)